skincancer.org 2019-03-11

# Privacy Policy - SkinCancer.org

#### We’re Committed to Your Privacy

Your privacy is important to The Skin Cancer Foundation (SCF). To protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

#### Types of Personal Information that We Collect

When you engage with the Foundation or visit or use our online donation and sales systems, we collect a variety of information. The type of information we collect will depend on the nature of the interaction. We may collect personal information in the following ways:

**Contact Information and Demographics**  
We may collect your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number(s) and limited location information.

**Financial Information**  
If you make a donation to the Foundation or make a purchase through the SCF store, we will collect payment information such as your credit card number to process your transaction. We use a third-party payment service to process payments. We will retain your credit card information only for as long as necessary to process the transaction(s).

**Location, Web Behavior and Technology**  
We may capture the IP address and ID of the device you use to connect to the online service, the type of operating system and browser you use, and information about the site you came from, the parts of our online service you access, the type of mobile device you use and the site you visit next.

**Call Notes/ Recordings**  
If you call SCF, we may take notes detailing the nature of the call and/or record the call for training and quality assurance purposes. The information contained in these transcripts will depend on what you voluntarily provide to the SCF.

#### How We Use This Information

We use the information discussed above in a number of ways, such as:

  * Processing donations and purchase transactions;
  * Responding to your requests and communicating with you;
  * Managing your preferences;
  * Performing analytics concerning your use of our online services, including your responses to our emails and the pages and advertisements you view;
  * Providing you tailored content and marketing messages;
  * Operating, evaluating and improving our programs (including developing new products and services; improving existing products and services; performing data analytics; and performing accounting, auditing and other internal functions);
  * Complying with and enforcing applicable legal requirements, relevant industry standards, contractual obligations and our policies;
  * For any other purposes that we may specifically disclose at the time you provide or we collect your information.

We may also use data that we collect on an aggregate or anonymous basis for various purposes, where permissible under applicable laws and regulations, to help deliver products, services and content that are better tailored to the users of our services and for other purposes.

#### Sharing of Personal Information

The Skin Cancer Foundation may need to share personal information with third parties in limited circumstances. For example, we may share your information with:

  * Credit card processing companies to process your payments and donations;
  * Website host and/or web analytics provider;
  * Vendors for the purpose of providing customer support or fulfilling orders placed through our store;
  * Other third parties to comply with legal requirements such as the demands of applicable subpoenas and court orders; to verify or enforce our terms of use, our other rights or other applicable policies; to address fraud, security or technical issues; to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property or security of our customers or third parties.

All third parties are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of personal information and are not authorized to use personal information for any purpose other than providing those services.

#### Updating Your Information and Opting Out

You may update your contact information, determine your preferences or opt-in/opt-out online preferences by contacting the SCF:

  1. [Email our team](mailto:info@skincancer.org).
  2. Follow directions on a marketing e-mail communication from us; or
  3. Send a request to:

The Skin Cancer Foundation  
205 Lexington Avenue, 11th Floor  
New York, NY 10016  
ATTN: Privacy Team

#### Links to Third-Party Websites

SCF may provide links to websites that are owned or operated by others ("third-party websites"). When you use a link online to visit a third-party website, you will be subject to that website’s privacy and security practices, which may differ from ours. You should familiarize yourself with the privacy policy, terms of use and security practices of the linked third-party website before providing any information on that website.

#### Changes to This Privacy Statement

We may change this Privacy Statement from time to time. When we do, we will let you know by appropriate means such as by posting the revised policy on this page with a new “Last Updated” date. In some cases, you may be asked to agree again to our Privacy Policy or other terms, even if you have already agreed to accept them, because there were changes. Any changes to this Privacy Statement will become effective when posted unless indicated otherwise.

_**Last Updated: 05/29/2018**_
